CURRICULUM VITAE

MIGUEL PALENCIA DE MIGUEL

PHONE NUMBER: (+34) 630 323 420

EMAIL ADDRESS: MIGUELPALENCIADEMI@GMAIL.COM

COUNTRY: SPAIN

PORTFOLIO: HTTPS://MIGUELPALENCIADEMI.GITHUB.IO/



PERSONAL PROFILE

I am Video game Design and Development graduate and specialized in the programming department at ESNE.

As a programmer, what motivates me the most is to solve the numerous challenges that arise when it comes to the development video game mechanics. I like finding the simplest and fastest solution to solve a problem since this way it is easier for my colleagues. I could say that my main ability is adapting to the different sudden changes that occur throughout the development.

The most ambitious project I have worked on is my Final Grade Project, Relight by DreamStudio. In that project I take the role of Gameplay programmer. In addition to composing the main ambient sound.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

//Advance knowledge of C++
//Advance knowledge of C#
//Advance knowledge of Js
//Knowledge of Adobe Illustrator
//Knowledge of Adobe Premiere
//Knowledge of Adobe Photoshop
//Knowledge of Adobe Illustrator
//Knowledge of Adobe Illustrator
//Knowledge of Adobe Photoshop
//Knowledge of Adobe Premiere

EDUCATION

VIDEOGAMES DESIGN AND DEVELOPMENT AT ESNE (SEPTEMBER 2015 - JULY 2019)

4TH YEAR

//Graphic Engine and Plugins (C++)

//3DMax: Maxscript *

//Video game Production

//Middleware: Development tools(C++)

//Advance 3D: OpenGL (C++)

//Advance animation 3D (C++)

//IA (Unity3D/C#)

//Graphic Programming (Unity3D)

//Final Grade Project

3RD. 2ND & 1ST YEAR

//Curricular Internship *

//Web video game development **

//Object Oriented Programming *

//Audio on Video games

* S GRADES

** HIGH HONORS

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

INTERNSHIP AT OPENMAGS (NOVEMBER 2017 - APRIL 2018)

HTTPS://WEB.OPENMAGS.COM/ES/

Internship in the programming department. Development of templates for the Openmags platform where the user can customize their own publications.

I made templates about newsletters, magazines, presentations and portfolios. The main code was made in JavaScript.

RESPONSIBILITIES

//Design and create new templates

//Debug code from other programmers

//Redesign and fix old publications

OTHER EXPERIENCE

ARTIST AND PRODUCTION ASSISTANT AT BLUEBERRY STUDIOS (JULY 2018 - PRESENT)

HTTPS://WWW.BLUEBERRYSTUDIOS.ES/

AS ARTIST

//3D background modeling

//Background illustrator

AS PRODUCTION ASSISTANT

//I am part of the production team of the "Bajo mi piel" project, it is aimed at schools and high schools to deal with important social issues such as bullying.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

ENGLISH

//Medium - High

//Comenius Project 2014

//English course in Exemouth (Devon, England) 2012/13/14/15

//Stay during the month of April 2017 in Berkely (San Francisco)

HOBBIES AND INTEREST

My main interests are videogames and music.

As for videogames, I prefer games that give total freedom for the players creativity, allowing you to create your own adventures. I am very impressed by Media Molecule games, such as "Little Big Planet" or "Dreams". Although I must admit that the world of Skyrim is my favorite to get lost in.

The Elder Scrolls and The Legend of Zelda are the sagas that made me realised my passion for ambiental music destined to video games, especially the way music and environment complement each other. Due to this passion, my end of career research is about how music affects the player.